GURAN VUGIC

EXPERIENCED WEB & MOBILE DEVELOPER

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Languages:

JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Python

Front-end Frameworks:

React, Vue, Electron, Flutter Web

Back-end Frameworks:

Node.js, Express, Nest.js, Net, Laravel, Django

Mobile App Frameworks:

React Native, Flutter

Cloud Services:

AWS Amplify, AWS Lambda, Amazon DynamoDB, S3, AWS Cognito, EC2, Cloud Firestore, Firebase Realtime database, Firebase gateway

DevOps:

Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Docker, CI/CD, Webpack, Jest, Mocha, Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Waterfall, TDD, SOLID, DRY

Engineering & Technology: Software Engineering, Reverse

Engineering, Artificial Intelligence

CONTACT DETAILS

Address:

Brus, Serbia

LinkedIn:

www.linkedin.com/in/guran-vugic-

Email:

vugicguran@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

Experienced and detail-oriented Web & Mobile App Developer with a knack for conceptualizing an delivering elegant, user- friendly solutions effectively and efficiently. Have 8 years of experience as a Full Stack Developer, specialized in Modern JS and PHP frameworks. Love to collaborate with team actively, eager to take a challenge with new technologies and Having creative collaboration.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Full Stack Developer

Self-employed | June 2021

React / Node Developer

Rpptr Labs | Feb 20219 - June 2021

- Improved a FinTech platform on the Frontend side and API implementation in React
- The developed mobile app from desktop web version with Firebase
- Added 30+ components to be used in the global app by using styled-components
- Redesigned global state management system with Redux thunk
- Simplified and improved UX from new design
- Improved performance by optimizing codes with modern JS and API handling
- Developed Admin panel with React and Node

Full-stack Developer

Rpptr Labs | Sep 2017 - Feb 2019

- Developed headless CMS with React.js, Node.js, and Strapi
- Upgraded a powerful SaaS using Vue.js and Vuex, Vuetify framework
- Updated and added new RESTful APIs by using Apollo GraphQL + AWS Lambda function
- Improved search algorithm and architecture (+30% Big O)
- Implemented Aherf service for SEO and added JSON-LD for better search user experience.
- Increased CTR(Clickthrough rate) depends on A/B tests (+24% improved)
- Integrated payment gateway (stripe API) and localized by using i18n
- Transformed localStorage-based state management to Vue x-based system
- Contributed to the in-browser slide generator and renderer using VueJS

Frontend Developer

PureNet | Aug 2015 - Sep 2017

- Acted as a Full Stack developer in a 30+ dev team for 2 years
- Improved UI/UX with React, Node, styled-components, d3.js, TradingView
- Developed and improved performance of +10 animation effects with custom styling
- Simplified global state management by using Mobx
- Suggested and Integrated real-time communication mechanism with Socket.IO and ws(npm package)

Software Developer

Endava | Feb 2014 - Aug 2016

- Built from scratch admin platform for managing platform's database entities and users using React.
- Implemented complex UI components with React/TypeScript and SCSS.
- Improved the UX by creating several DnD-based components.
- Wrote scripts to use and manipulate data from various sources.

EDUCATION

University of Novi Sad, Faculty of Technical Sciences Bachelor's Degree | 2009 - 2013